Guide to the Jewish Heritage Foundation of North Carolina Oral History Collection, 1981-2014 RL.11031
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jewish Heritage Foundation of North Carolina oral history collection
1981-2014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jewish Heritage Foundation of North Carolina
Rogoff, Leonard
Gruber, Robin
Channing, Steven A.
RL.11031
5.3 Linear Feet
The oral history video recordings, audio recordings, and transcripts in this collection were produced or collected by the Jewish Heritage Foundation of North Carolina (JHFNC) and historian Leonard Rogoff as source material for various projects related to the history of Jews in North Carolina. The collection consists of individual and group interviews of Jewish residents of urban and rural North Carolina, including rabbis. Topics discussed by interviewees include family and community history, religious education, participation in Jewish congregations, anti-Semitism and race relations the civil rights movement in North Carolina, World War II military service and the Holocaust, family businesses, and philanthropy. Interviewers include Rogoff, Robin Gruber, and Steven Channing.
Access Restrictions
Access note. Collection contains electronic records that may need to be reformatted. Access copies of electronic records require special equipment. Contact Research Services for access.
Arrangement
The interviews in this collection are organized into the following series: Asheville and surrounding areas, Charlotte and surrounding areas, Durham, and surrounding areas, Fayetteville and surrounding areas, Goldsboro and surrounding areas, Greensboro and surrounding areas, Raleigh, Weldon and surrounding areas, Wilmington and surrounding areas, Winston-Salem and surrounding areas, and Oral history resources.
Within each series, the interviews are arranged alphabetically by interviewee last name.
Collection Overview
The oral history video recordings, audio recordings, and transcripts in this collection were created or collected by the Jewish Heritage Foundation of North Carolina (JHFNC) and historian Leonard Rogoff as source material for various projects related to the history of Jews in North Carolina. The collection consists of individual and group interviews of Jewish residents of urban and rural North Carolina, including rabbis and elected public officials. Families represented include the Brenner, Cone, Evans, Kittner, and Samet families. Topics discussed by interviewees include family and community history, religious education, participation in Jewish congregations, anti-Semitism and race relations in North Carolina, World War II military service and the Holocaust, family businesses, and philanthropy.
The JHFNC projects for which the oral histories were created include the museum exhibit "Migrations: Jewish settlers of eastern North Carolina" (2000-2002), the book "A history of Temple Emanu-El: an extended family, Weldon, North Carolina" (2007), and the museum exhibit, documentary film, and book "Down Home: Jewish life in North Carolina" (2007-2012). Unaffiliated projects from which the JHFNC collected oral histories include the Duke University undergraduate honors thesis "From Pine Street to Watts Street: an oral history of the Jews of Durham, North Carolina" by Robin Gruber (1986), the oral history project of the 1986 Beth El Synagogue (Durham) Confirmation class, Rogoff's book "Homelands: southern Jewish identity in Durham and Chapel Hill, North Carolina" (2001), and the Steven Channing documentary film "Durham: a self-portrait," which shares video interview footage with "Down Home." Some of the media on which the oral histories were recorded contain additional video footage used for "Down Home" or "Durham: a self-portrait."
The majority of the interviews were performed by Leonard Rogoff and volunteers from the profiled Jewish communities. Other interviewers include Robin Gruber, Steven Sager, Steven Channing, Sharon Fahrer, and Jan Schochet.
Historical note
The Jewish Heritage Foundation of North Carolina (JHFNC) is an independent organization dedicated to preserving and presenting the history of the Jewish people of North Carolina. Through public programming and exhibits, the JHFNC aspires to educate and showcase the richness of Jewish Life as well as promote a familiarity with the culture and lifestyle of Jews to the general public.
In 2014, the JHFNC transferred their historical collections to the Rubenstein Library, including the oral history recordings and transcripts.
Related Material
Jewish Heritage Foundation of North Carolina records, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
North Carolina temple and synagogue historical collection, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Beth-El Synagogue records, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Evans family papers, 1920s-1990s, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Antisemitism -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Jewish families -- North Carolina; Jews -- North Carolina -- Social life and customs; Jews -- North Carolina -- History; Jews -- United States -- Identity; Rabbis -- North Carolina; Synagogues -- North Carolina; World War, 1939-1945 -- Jews -- United States; North Carolina -- Race relations; Oral histories (document genre); Audiovisual materials; Video recordings
- Asheville and surrounding areas, 2003-2007; 1
  Scope and Contents
  Geographic locations represented in this series include Asheville, Brevard, Burnsville, Hendersonville, and Camp Blue Star.
  - Bernstein, William and Katherine (Burnsville), 2007; 1
    - William and Katherine Bernstein. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 16; digital betacam, 1 of 2 (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-018)
      Container label: "Exteriors- walking to seminars; cantor singing... lunch with B'nai Brith attendees...Wild Acres…glassblowers - Bernsteins"
    - William and Katherine Bernstein. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 16; digital betacam, 2 of 2 (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-019)
      Container label: "Bernstein's glass pieces, Yaffa Sikorski [Sikorsky-Todd] & Jeff Todd, Rob Levin"
  - Bossert, Norman (Brevard), 2005; 2
    - Norman Bossert. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2005 June 21; audiocassette (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-058)
      Container label: "6/21/05 Asheville NC; Norman Bossert; Brevard Jewish Community; Interviewer: Leonard Rogoff"
    - Norman Bossert. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2005 June 21; transcript (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Eisenberg, Barry (Hendersonville / Camp Blue Star), 2007; 3
    - Barry Eisenberg. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 16; audiocassette (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-022)
      Container label: "Blue Star - Walter Solomon, Barry Eisenberg, Rodger Popkin"
    - Barry Eisenberg. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 16; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-020)
      Container label: "Camp Blue Star, Vicky and Roger [Rodger] Popkin, Rosalee [Rosalie] Popkin, Archery - kids, Photo of camp - Kiddush Prayer, Barry Eisenberg, Shabbat Service"
  - Fahrer, Sharon, 2007; 4
    - Sharon Fahrer. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 18; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-020)
      Container label: "Asheville: Jan Schocket, Sharon Fahrer"
  - Kaplan, Morris (Hendersonville), 2005; 5
    - Morris Kaplan. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2005 June 21; audiocassette (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-013)
      Container label: "Morris Kaplan, Hendersonville, Agudas Israel Cong."
    - Morris Kaplan. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2005 June 21; transcript (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Kligerman, Vicky Popkin (Hendersonville / Camp Blue Star), 2007; 6
    - Vicky Popkin Kligerman. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 17; digital betacam, 1 of 2 (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-019)
      Container label: "Camp Blue Star, Miles Kutler [Kuttler], Roger [Rodger] Popkin and Vicky Kligerman"
    - Vicky Popkin Kligerman. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 17; digital betacam, 2 of 2 (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-020)
  - Kuttler, Miles (Hendersonville / Camp Blue Star), 2007; 7
    - Miles Kuttler. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 17; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-019)
  - Levin, Rob (Burnsville), 2007; 8
    - Rob Levin. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 16; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-019)
    - Rob Levin. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 16; transcript (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Lurey, Milton (Hendersonville), 2003; 9
    - Milton Lurey. Interviewed by Sharon Fahrer and Jan Schochet, 2003 August 6; mini-dv, 1 of 2 (Box 5, Video-cassette RL11031-MDV-001)
      Container label: "Milton Lurey Tape 1"
    - Milton Lurey. Interviewed by Sharon Fahrer and Jan Schochet, 2003 August 6; mini-dv, 2 of 2 (Box 5, Video-cassette RL11031-MDV-002)
      Container label: "Milton Lurey Tape 2"
    - Milton Lurey. Interviewed by Sharon Fahrer and Jan Schochet, 2003 August 6; index (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Patton, Marilyn Blomberg, 2004; 10
    - Marilyn Blomberg Patton. Interviewed by Sharon Fahrer, 2004 February 23; mini-dv (Box 5, Video-cassette RL11031-MDV-004)
      Container label: "Marilyn Blomberg Patton"
    - Marilyn Blomberg Patton. Interviewed by Sharon Fahrer, 2004 February 23; index (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Popkin, Rodger (Hendersonville / Camp Blue Star), 2007; 11
    - Rodger Popkin. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 16; audiocassette (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-022)
    - Rodger Popkin. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 17; digital betacam, 1 of 2 (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-019)
    - Rodger Popkin. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 17; digital betacam, 2 of 2 (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-020)
  - Popkin, Rosalie (Hendersonville / Camp Blue Star), 2007; 12
    - Rosalie Popkin. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 17; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-020)
  - Robinson, Michael Aaron, Rabbi, 2003; 13
    - Rabbi Michael Aaron Robinson. Interviewed by Sharon Fahrer?, 2003 July 17; mini-dv (Box 5, Video-cassette RL11031-MDV-003)
      Container label: "Tape #2 Rabbi Robinson"
    - Rabbi Michael Aaron Robinson. Interviewed by Sharon Fahrer?, 2003 July 17; index (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Schochet, Jan, 2007; 14
    - Jan Schochet. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 18; digital betacam, 1 of 3 (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-020)
      Container label: "Asheville: Jan Schocket [Schochet], Sharon Fahrer"
    - Jan Schochet. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 18; digital betacam, 2 of 3 (Box 7, Audio-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-021)
      Container label: "Asheville: Julienne Winner, Asheville Cemetary, Jan Schocket [Schochet]
    - Jan Schochet. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 18; digital betacam, 3 of 3 (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-022)
      Container label: "Jan Schocket [Schochet], placards, JCC/Beth Ha Tephila Reform, Beth Israel, Sylvia and Karl Straus; Gordon Scrapyard - Statesville - Saul and Kalman"
  - Solomon, Walter (Hendersonville / Camp Blue Star), 2007; 15
    - Walter Solomon. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 16; audiocassette (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-022)
  - Sternberg, Jerry, 2007; 16
    - Jerry Sternberg. Interviewed for Down Home project, 2007 October 20; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-025)
      Container label: "Asheville - Blue Ridge Parkway, Jerry Sternberg, Hard Lox Jewish Festival, Rabbi Susskind"
  - Straus, Sylvia and Karl, 2007; 17
    - Sylvia and Karl Straus. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 17; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-022)
      Container label: "Jan Schocket, placards, JCC/Beth Ha Tephila Reform, Beth Israel, Sylvia and Karl Straus; Gordon Scrapyard - Statesville - Saul and Kalman"
  - Susskind, Shaya, Rabbi, 2007; 18
    - Rabbi Shaya Susskind. Interviewed for Down Home project, 2007 October 20; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-025)
  - Todd, Jeff and Yaffa Sikorsky (Burnsville), 2007; 19
    - Jeff and Yaffa Sikorsky Todd. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 16; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-019)
  - Winner, Julienne, 2007; 20
    - Julienne Winner. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 August 18; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-021)
      Container label: "Asheville: Julienne Winner, Asheville Cemetary, Jan Schocket [Schochet]"
- Charlotte and surrounding areas, 2005-2009; 2
  Geographic locations represented in this series include Charlotte and Gastonia.
  - Blumenthal, Phillip, 2007; 21
    - Phillip Blumenthal. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 June 13; digital betacam (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-016)
      Container label: "Wilmington: Nathan Schwartz int.; Walter Klein, Phillip Blumenthal"
  - Klein, Walter, 2007; 22
    - Walter Klein. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 June 13; digital betacam (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-016)
  - Chenkin, Suly, 2007; 23
    - Suly Chenkin. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 June 13; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-017)
      Container label: "Charlotte: Jubans; Greensboro: Elsewhere Artist Collaborative"
  - Goldstein, Alwyn Oscar, 2006; 24
    - Alwyn Oscar Goldstein. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2006 April 18; digital betacam (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-006)
      Container label: "Marshall Rauch/Alwyn Oscar Goldstein"
    - Alwyn Oscar Goldstein. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2006 April 18; transcript (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Gorelick, William, 2006; 25
    - William Gorelick. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2006 November 22; digital betacam (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-009)
      Container label: "William (Bill) Gorelick"
    - William Gorelick. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2006 November 22; DVD (Box 6, Video-disc RL11031-DVD-002)
      Container label: "Interview with Bill Gorelick"
    - William Gorelick. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2006 November 22; detailed summary (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Grosswald, Esther, circa 2009; 26
    - Esther Grosswald. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, circa 2009; audiocassette (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-018)
      Container label: "Esther Grosswald"
  - Levin, Jerry, 2005; 27
    - Jerry Levin. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2005 June 2; digital betacam (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-002)
      Container label: "Jerry Levin"
    - Jerry Levin. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2005 June 2; transcript (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Levine, Sandra and Leon, 2006; 28
    - Sandra and Leon Levine. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2006 November 22; digital betacam (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-010)
      Container label: "Sandra and Leon Levine"
    - Sandra and Leon Levine. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2006 November 22; transcript (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Rauch, Marshall Arthur (Gastonia), 2006; 29
    - Marshall Arthur Rauch. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2006 April 18; digital betacam (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-006)
    - Marshall Arthur Rauch. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2006 April 18; transcript (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Rosenberg, Thomas S. and Zahava, 2007; 30
    - Thomas S.and Zahava Rosenberg. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 June 13; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-017)
  - Schindler, Judy, Rabbi, 2006; 31
    - Rabbi Judy Schindler. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2006 April 18; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-027)
      Container label: "Rabbi Schindler"
    - Rabbi Judy Schindler. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2006 April 18; transcript (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Wojnowich, Mary and Simon, 2007; 32
    - Mary and Simon Wojnowich. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Down Home project, 2007 June 13; digital betacam (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11031-Dbcam-017)
- Durham and surrounding areas, 1981; 1986-2008; 2014; undated; 3
  Geographic locations represented in this series include Chapel Hill, Durham, and Oxford, North Carolina.
  - Bane, Henry, 1985-1986; 33
    - Henry Bane. Interviewed by Robin Gruber for Duke University oral history seminar, 1985 November 19; audiocassette (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-100, Digital-materials RL11031-SET-0001, Audio-file rl11031_cs_100_001.wav, Audio-file rl11031_cs_100_002.wav)
      Container label: "Henry Bane"
    - Henry Bane. Interviewed by Robin Gruber for Duke University oral history seminar, 1985 November 19; detailed summary (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Henry Bane. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Jewish community of Durham-Chapel Hill oral history project, 1986 September; audiocassette, 1 of 2 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-045, Digital-materials RL11031-SET-0001, Audio-file rL11031_cs_045_001.wav, Audio-file rl11031_cs_045_002.wav)
    - Henry Bane. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Jewish community of Durham-Chapel Hill oral history project, 1986 September; audiocassette, 2 of 2 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-046, Digital-materials RL11031-SET-0001, Audio-file rl11031_cs_046_001.wav)
      Container label: "Henry Bane Tape 2"
    - Henry Bane. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Jewish community of Durham-Chapel Hill oral history project, 1986 September; transcript (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Henry Bane. Interviewed by Beth El Synagogue Confirmation class, 1986 April 1; audiocassette (Box 3, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-099)
      Container label: "Judge Bane - April 1; Beth-Nina"
  - Berger, Herbert, Rabbi, 1994; 34
    - Rabbi Herbert Berger. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Homelands project, 1994 February 9; detailed summary (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Bergman, Harry, circa 1986; 35
    - Harry Bergman. Interviewed by Violet Tartell for Jewish community of Durham-Chapel Hill oral history project, circa 1986; audiocassette (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-054)
      Container label: "Harry Bergman"
    - Harry Bergman. Interviewed by Violet Tartell for Jewish community of Durham-Chapel Hill oral history project, circa 1986; detailed summary (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Bernson, Ethel Mae Zuckerman, 1986; 1992; 36
    - Ethel Mae Zuckerman Bernson. Interviewed by Robin Gruber for Duke University oral history seminar, 1986 February 2; audiocassette (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-065)
      Container label: "Ethel May Bernson"
    - Ethel Mae Zuckerman Bernson. Interviewed by Robin Gruber for Duke University oral history seminar, 1986 February 2; detailed summary (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Ethel Mae Bernson and Hazel Gladstein Wishnov. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Homelands project, 1992 April 27; audiocassette (Box 5, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-166)
    - Ethel Mae Bernson and Hazel Gladstein Wishnov. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Homelands project, 1992 April 27; transcript (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Beth El Synagogue, 1981; 1986; 37
    - Beth El Synagogue - luncheon discussion. Interviewed by Rabbi Steve Sager and Beth-El Confirmation class, 1981 May 14; audiocassette (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-006)
      Interviewees include George and Ricki Lewin, Anna and Sigmund Meyer, May Segal, and Pat Silver. Container label: "Luncheon discussion w/Sigmund, Anna Meyers [Meyer], George & Ricki Levin [Lewin], Pat Silver, May Segal"
    - Beth El Synagogue - presidents. Interviewed by Sheldon Hanft for Jewish community of Durham-Chapel Hill oral history project, 1986 September 1; microcassette (Box 5, Audio-cassette RL11031-MCS-001)
      Interviewees include Henry Bane, Emanuel J. "Mutt" Evans, Gilbert "Gibby" Katz, Norman Lefstein, Peter Ornstein, Joel Schwartz, Melvin Shimm, Gladys Siegel, and Lewis Siegel. Container label: "Beth El Pres"
    - Beth El Synagogue - presidents. Interviewed by Sheldon Hanft for Jewish community of Durham-Chapel Hill oral history project, 1986 September 1; microcassette (Box 5, Audio-cassette RL11031-MCS-002)
    - Beth El Synagogue - presidents. Interviewed by Sheldon Hanft for Jewish community of Durham-Chapel Hill oral history project, 1986 September 1; audiocassette, 1 of 2 (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-029)
      Interviewees include Henry Bane, Emanuel J. "Mutt" Evans, Gilbert "Gibby" Katz, Norman Lefstein, Peter Ornstein, Joel Schwartz, Melvin Shimm, Gladys Siegel, and Lewis Siegel. Container label: "Beth El presidents - Tape 1, 9/86"
    - Beth El Synagogue - presidents. Interviewed by Sheldon Hanft for Jewish community of Durham-Chapel Hill oral history project, 1986 September 1; audiocassette, 2 of 2 (Box 5, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-162)
      Interviewees include Henry Bane, Emanuel J. "Mutt" Evans, Gilbert "Gibby" Katz, Norman Lefstein, Peter Ornstein, Joel Schwartz, Melvin Shimm, Gladys Siegel, and Lewis Siegel. Container label: "[Pres. Mtg. Beth El]"
  - Blum, Dorothy, 1986; 38
    - Dorothy Blum. Interviewed by Lori Posner for Jewish community of Durham-Chapel Hill oral history project, 1986 May 23; audiocassette (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-025)
      Container label: "Dorothy Blum interviewed by Lori Posner, Chapel Hill, NC 27514"
    - Dorothy Blum. Interviewed by Lori Posner for Jewish community of Durham-Chapel Hill oral history project, 1986 May 23; detailed summary (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Brady, Lehman, 1986; 39
    - Lehman Brady. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff for Jewish community of Durham-Chapel Hill oral history project, 1986 October 1; detailed summary (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Brandt, Yetta Sawilowsky, 1986; 40
    - Yetta Sawilowsky Brandt. Interviewed by Robin Gruber for Duke University oral history seminar, 1986 February 2; detailed summary (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Cohen, Sarah (Chapel Hill), 1987; 41
    - Sarah Cohen. Interviewed by Judith Siegel for Jewish community of Durham-Chapel Hill oral history project, 1987 January 1; audiocassette (Box 1, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-027)
      Container label: "Sarah Cohen"
    - Sarah Cohen. Interviewed by Judith Siegel for Jewish community of Durham-Chapel Hill oral history project, 1987 January 1; transcript (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Dworsky, Leon, 1985-1987; 42
    - Leon Dworsky. Interviewed by Robin Gruber for Duke University oral history seminar, 1985 November 6; detailed summary (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Leon Dworsky. Interviewed by Robin Gruber for Duke University oral history seminar, 1986 January 26; detailed summary (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Leon Dworsky. Interviewed by Rabbi Steven Sager and Beth-El Confirmation class, 1986 March 25; audiocassette (Box 4, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-123)
      Container label: "Leon & Phyllis Dworsky"
    - Leon Dworsky. Interviewed by Leonard Rogoff? for Jewish community of Durham-Chapel Hill oral history project, circa 1986-1987; audiocassette (Box 5, Audio-cassette RL11031-CS-155, Digital-materials RL11031-SET-0001, Audio-file rl11031_cs_155_001.wav, Audio-file rl11031_cs_155_002.wav)